<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>A Hugo website</title>
    <link>http://john-ensley.com/projecteuler/</link>
    <description>Recent content on A Hugo website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://john-ensley.com/projecteuler/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Problem 7: 10001st prime</title>
      <link>http://john-ensley.com/projecteuler/7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://john-ensley.com/projecteuler/7/</guid>
      <description>Problem  By listing the first six prime numbers: 2, 3, 5, 7, 11, and 13, we can see that the 6th prime is 13.
What is the 10 001st prime number?
  Explanation We’ve already implemented the sieve of Eratosthenes, a method for generating all primes less than some \(n\). In order to use that, we’ll need to know some value of \(n\) such that there will be at least 10,001 prime numbers less than \(n\).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Problem 6: Sum square difference</title>
      <link>http://john-ensley.com/projecteuler/6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://john-ensley.com/projecteuler/6/</guid>
      <description>Problem  The sum of the squares of the first ten natural numbers is,
 \[ 1^2 + 2^2 + \dots + 10^2 = 385 \]
 The square of the sum of the first ten natural numbers is,
 \[ (1 + 2 + ... + 10)^2 = 55^2 = 3025 \]
 Hence the difference between the sum of the squares of the first ten natural numbers and the square of the sum is 3025 − 385 = 2640.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Problem 5: Smallest multiple</title>
      <link>http://john-ensley.com/projecteuler/5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://john-ensley.com/projecteuler/5/</guid>
      <description>Problem  2520 is the smallest number that can be divided by each of the numbers from 1 to 10 without any remainder.
What is the smallest positive number that is evenly divisible by all of the numbers from 1 to 20?
  Explanation This problem boils down to finding the least common multiple of all numbers from 1 to 20. ⊕The least common multiple, or LCM, of two integers \(a\) and \(b\) is the smallest positive integer that is divisible by both \(a\) and \(b\).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Problem 4: Largest palindrome product</title>
      <link>http://john-ensley.com/projecteuler/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://john-ensley.com/projecteuler/4/</guid>
      <description>Problem  A palindromic number reads the same both ways. The largest palindrome made from the product of two 2-digit numbers is 9009 = 91 × 99.
Find the largest palindrome made from the product of two 3-digit numbers.
  Explanation The overall approach for this problem is very simple: we’ll loop through all combinations of two three-digit numbers, multiply them, and see if the product is a palindrome or not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Problem 3: Largest prime factor</title>
      <link>http://john-ensley.com/projecteuler/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://john-ensley.com/projecteuler/3/</guid>
      <description>Problem  The prime factors of 13195 are 5, 7, 13 and 29.
What is the largest prime factor of the number 600851475143 ?
  Explanation Every integer greater than 1 is either a prime number or can be represented as the product of prime numbers. ⊕That’s the fundamental theorem of arithmetic. The most straightforward approach for solving this problem is to simply walk through the prime numbers less than \(n = 600851475143\) and try dividing each of them into \(n\).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Problem 2: Even Fibonacci numbers</title>
      <link>http://john-ensley.com/projecteuler/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://john-ensley.com/projecteuler/2/</guid>
      <description>Problem  Each new term in the Fibonacci sequence is generated by adding the previous two terms. By starting with 1 and 2, the first 10 terms will be:
1, 2, 3, 5, 8, 13, 21, 34, 55, 89, …
By considering the terms in the Fibonacci sequence whose values do not exceed four million, find the sum of the even-valued terms.
  Explanation The naive approach works just fine here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Problem 1: Multiples of 3 and 5</title>
      <link>http://john-ensley.com/projecteuler/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://john-ensley.com/projecteuler/1/</guid>
      <description>Problem  If we list all the natural numbers below 10 that are multiples of 3 or 5, we get 3, 5, 6 and 9. The sum of these multiples is 23.
Find the sum of all the multiples of 3 or 5 below 1000.
  Explanation We start out with an easy one. There are a ton of different ways to get the correct sum. Since R is so vectorized, I feel like the most R-like way is to avoid any loops and deal with vectors instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://john-ensley.com/projecteuler/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 21:48:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://john-ensley.com/projecteuler/about/</guid>
      <description>This is a &amp;ldquo;hello world&amp;rdquo; example website for the blogdown package. The theme was forked from @jrutheiser/hugo-lithium-theme and modified by Yihui Xie.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>